-== [ www.OpenSubtitles.org ] ==-
[♪ legendary music playing]
[lightsaber activates]
[♪ music fades]
[whooshes]
[silence]
-[laser booming]
-[gasps]
[rumbling]
-[people screaming]
-[gasps]
-[rumbling]
-[all gasping]
[miner] What is that?
[♪ sinister music playing]
[♪ music ends]
-[citizens murmuring]
-[gasps]
[citizens exclaiming]
[all screaming]
[♪ tense music playing]
Bibin must be evacuated immediately.
Our people
will need all the help they can get
-in order to fly off this planet safely.
-[Kwana] Hurry!
[electronic beeping]
[Gennoh] The beam missed?
[Nawaam] Fire the second shot.
Sir.
[digital beeping]
[weapon whirring]
[weapon powering up]
[gasps]
-[electricity crackling]
-[scientist screams]
-[Zhima gasps]
-[Nawaam gasps]
[scientists whimpering]
[exclaims]
-[electricity buzzing]
-[Nawaam grunts]
[scientists screaming]
[panting. gasps]
-[screams]
-[metal creaks]
[gasps]
[straining]
[♪ tense music playing]
[bubbling]
[whooshes]
[Kwana] Remain calm. everyone.
Everything will be all right.
-[man] Kwana.
-[Kwana] Hmm?
There aren't enough ships
to evacuate everyone.
-Hmm.
-[indistinct chatter]
Unload all the ore from the cargo holds.
Everyone. you'll have
to leave your belongings.
We must work together so we can get
as many people as possible on board.
-[citizens murmuring]
-[device beeps]
I'm calling all Asteroid Diggers
to assist us.
[over comms] We don't have enough ships
to evacuate Bibin.
Please. we need one of your ships
to transport refugees.
-[grunts]
-Hmm.
-[Kara panting]
-[beeping]
Ethan?
I'm so glad you're alive. Juro.
Thanks.
The power of that beam
is beyond what I could have imagined.
What kind of weapon are we dealing with.
and where is he hiding?
The enemy's stronghold is on Yaago.
Nawaam's engineers
built a powerful cannon.
and its energy source
appears to be kyber crystals.
But I don't know how it reached Bibin.
I'll keep investigating
and get back to you.
Right. But make sure you're on your guard.
-[warbles]
-Hmm.
[distant explosions]
[panting]
-[panting]
-[rumbling]
-[crashing]
-[grunts. panting]
[powering up]
[doors hissing]
[metallic creaking]
[panting] It's been a while.
[droid beeping]
[Tafflah] An old reliable ship has been
found at the palace maintenance deck.
-[rumbling]
-Standby at the port.
-[gasps]
-[crashing]
[exclaims]
[thuds. explodes]
[engines powering up]
[indistinct chatter]
-[child whimpers]
-[citizen breathing heavily]
[engines whirring]
[sighs]
-[Juro and Kwana] Hmm?
-[Kara gasps]
[indistinct chatter]
[citizen] We're one of the search parties.
This is a log of who is accounted for.
[electronic beeping]
It seems that everyone else
is back at the port.
We can start evacuating now.
Where's Lady Tafflah?
[citizen] She said she was going
to the palace to secure a ship.
-[Kwana] I would like to speak to her.
-[citizen] Yes.
-[device beeps]
-Lady Tafflah.
Lady Tafflah?
-Do you read me. Lady Tafflah?
-[gasps]
[citizen] Lady Tafflah!
[engines revving]
[Kara panting]
This is the royal hangar.
There's a maintenance deck underground.
-[rumbling]
-[Juro grunts]
[Kara grunts. exclaims]
[lightsaber crackling]
[Tafflah panting]
[cracking]
-[lightsaber deactivates]
-[Kwana] Hmm.
[straining]
-[Kwana grunts]
-[door thuds]
[Kara panting]
[gasps]
-[clangs]
-[Kara grunts]
-[Tafflah yelps]
[Kara grunts. straining]
[grunts]
[straining]
[groans]
[both scream]
Kara!
-[rock thuds]
-[doors whirring]
[both straining]
[grunts]
[both grunting]
-[Tafflah panting]
-[Kara gasps]
[doors slam]
-[♪ tense music playing]
-[indistinct chatter]
[whimpering]
[citizen sobbing]
-[sighs. gasps]
-[engine whirring]
[chuckles]
[citizens gasping]
[both laugh]
Heh.
-[Kara] My Lady. are you all right?
-Hmm.
[Tafflah grunts]
-[droid whirring]
-[Kara] Huh?
[droid chirps]
[exhales]
[Kara] Juro. we're all right. but it looks
like the door is completely sealed.
-Understood.
-[Kwana grunts]
We'll find another way to get you two out.
Please stand by.
[grunts] Huh?
[Tafflah] It's broken.
And unfortunately. without it.
we don't have any other way
to open the hatch up there.
[Kara] Can it be done remotely?
If we sent a signal to one of the ships.
could they do it?
-[lightsaber buzzing]
-[gasps]
[Tafflah] Are you a Jedi?
Uh. I guess. Yeah.
I mean. I'm Juro's Padawan. So...
What is your name?
Kara.
-Kara. daughter of Lah Zhima.
-[gasps]
You know. Kwana said my father
was a master killer.
Can I ask. what exactly did my father do?
[silence]
[Tafflah] I didn't know
that he was still alive.
[Kwana] There should be a circuit
that controls that specific hatch.
Then that means we just need to figure out
how to divert power
and connect it back to that circuit.
[rumbling]
[Tafflah] I see.
Zhima ended up becoming a sabersmith.
Yes.
I have no idea what my father
was like as a Jedi.
He never shared stories from that time.
Of course you don't.
You know. in the end. the truth is.
I don't think any of us
really knew him at all.
[Kara] Um. did my father
actually kill his master?
Why would he do such a thing?
All I know for sure
is that Zhima did indeed
do what is claimed.
But why he did it is a question
that no one knows the answer to.
[sighs]
The Jedi had vanished quite some time ago.
There were few left who would even
be able to tell stories of them.
Reno Tsutara was among those few.
He arrived at Bibin alongside Juro.
Reno was one of the last 50
surviving Jedi Masters left.
He came to Bibin
with the goal of restoring the Order.
My people and I agreed with his vision
and decided to support it.
I thought the Order was fighting
for peace. free of other interests.
And that their success
would be beneficial.
[♪ gentle music playing]
Zhima was among the younglings
who had been gathered and brought here
from all corners of the galaxy.
And it did not take very long
before he became a standout.
So then my father was strong.
Yes.
Before long. Zhima and Juro
completed their training and became Jedi.
Reno sought to expand the Jedi Order.
And both Juro and Zhima
each took on Padawans at his behest.
Although Zhima wasn't exactly
a natural as a teacher.
he quickly began to enjoy it.
Around that time.
Reno began actively conducting
diplomatic missions
with other star systems.
He made great progress with trade as well.
This very ship
was the one he used for those missions.
At that time.
there was no central government.
As such. trade was not prosperous.
But leave it to Reno to somehow convince
other worlds to make him trade ambassador.
so he could help everyone
prosper and grow.
[inaudible conversation]
[Tafflah] When the head of a spaceport
from a wealthy family went missing.
he even stepped in to quell
the resulting internal struggle.
Thanks to that. Bibin's commerce expanded.
But behind the scenes.
Zhima was also becoming
quite a powerful figure.
My father?
[Tafflah] Reno would send him out
to fight any surviving Sith.
At the time. there were star systems
that employed Sith
to gain trade advantage.
Zhima was more than happy to fine-tune
his fighting skills with actual combat.
He truly believed that all these threats
should be eliminated
and that the galaxy would be
better off without the Sith.
However. the more Reno
became absorbed in politics.
the more Zhima appeared
to become absorbed in battle.
[gasps]
[whooshes]
Keep moving.
It's this way to the speeders.
Fit as many as you can.
-[citizens sobbing]
-Don't worry. my crew is coming back
with a larger ship to take everyone else.
Juro had decided to go to Hy Izlan.
which meant that Zhima was essentially
Reno's only remaining apprentice.
I accepted the fact
that the government and the Order
-mutually completed each other.
-[inaudible]
And that the power to preserve both
was being cultivated.
But Zhima rebelled.
saying that the Jedi
did not belong in politics.
So he clashed with Reno.
And then came the day.
the day of the incident.
[sighs]
[lightsabers crackling]
Please stop this!
[glass shatters]
-[lightsabers crackling]
-[Reno grunts]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[lasers firing]
[lightsaber buzzing]
-[rumbling]
-[lightsaber buzzing]
[♪ dramatic music continues]
[lightsaber crackling]
[both grunting]
-[Reno growls]
-[lightsaber warbles]
[Zhima gasps]
Wait. what? What is your lightsaber doing?
-I don't know.
-[warbling continues]
[Zhima grunts]
[♪ dramatic music continues]
[lightsaber buzzing]
[breathing heavily]
[warbling]
[high-pitched ringing]
[lightsaber buzzing]
[gasps]
[♪ dramatic music continues]
What color is that?
[warbling]
[♪ sinister music playing]
[gasps]
[body thuds]
[lightsaber deactivates]
[lasers firing]
[Tafflah] After that.
no one saw Zhima again.
That's everything.
I've now told you all that I know.
I ended up with no choice.
After the events of that day.
the Jedi Order had to be disbanded.
But why? Why would he do that?
I don't know.
I can only guess that perhaps
Zhima wished to prove himself
that he had surpassed his master.
It's hard to imagine.
I just can't picture my father
challenging his own master.
Not to mention. then killing him.
[Tafflah] That must be because
he was a good father to you.
However. when Zhima wielded
his lightsaber that day...
his eyes...
[whooshes]
Juro. the port won't hold out
for much longer.
We're almost there.
-[tools clinking]
-Hmm?
[doors hissing]
-[rumbling]
-[both gasp]
[both chuckle]
[both gasp]
-Isn't this...
-[thuds]
...Master Reno's ship?
Yes. I couldn't access it
from the docking bay before.
But it would seem like
that's no longer an issue.
[sighs]
[digital beeping]
So far. so good.
Would you mind if I took a look around?
There might be things we can move
to make room for more people.
[panting]
[exhales] Huh?
-[clicks]
-[door whirring]
[gasps]
Oh? [exhales]
[grunts softly]
[lights clicking]
-[air hisses]
-[thuds]
[screams. grunts]
[gasps] Who is that?
[whirring]
[♪ sinister music playing]
[Kara breathing heavily]
[switches clicking]
Not good. Too much time has passed.
[Kwana] Hey. Kara. you down here?
What's a staircase doing here? [gasps]
What is that?
[Tafflah] Ah. That's the leader of Baro Do
who went missing.
Reno chose his successor.
and that's when trading began.
What's he doing here?
Well. the good news is
that hidden hold is large.
It's approximately the size
of a Bibin ore hauler.
More than enough room
for the remaining civilians.
[grunts]
It seems there are some things we've yet
to learn about our old master.
For now. let's get to safety.
Let's go.
[engine powering up]
[distant explosions]
[sobbing]
-[ship approaches]
-[Homen gasps]
[engine powering down]
[citizens murmuring]
My people. we're here to evacuate you.
-[all gasping]
-[Tafflah] Begin boarding immediately.
Help each other.
and we will all make it aboard.
[explosions]
[engine roaring]
[rumbling]
[all grunting]
[whooshing]
[Juro] Master Reno
was replacing trade officials
in order to reap the profits from ore
being sold through illegal channels.
There is no justice in this.
We must now consider that our old master
succumbed to the dark side.
[sighs]
-[Kwana] Hmm.
-[gasps]
My father had a reason
to confront him then?
Yes.
[electronic beeping]
[Juro] Zhima was the one among us
-who was closest to Master Reno.
-[inaudible conversation]
Perhaps he was trying
to right our master's wrongs.
Yeah. good point. I'm sure that's it!
Uh...
[Kara sighs]
This is my fault.
It's all because I turned my back
and ignored the truth for so long
that this happened.
[stutters] Huh?
[grunts] Dank farrik.
We'll just have to ask Zhima himself.
[Kara and Homen] Hmm.
-[digital beeping]
-[Kara] Huh?
Glad to see you're all right.
What's the status?
[quietly] The main cannon malfunctioned.
-It seems to work like a giant lightsaber.
-[electricity crackling]
And I'm guessing that's the reason
why Nawaam needs Zhima.
Get this.
Nawaam can use the Force.
And for some reason.
he keeps calling Zhima "Master."
-[crackling]
-Uh... [gasps]
-[Four-Nines speaking Binary]
-[Ethan grunts]
-[footsteps departing]
-[both exhale]
-[grunts]
-[beeping]
-[gasps. groans]
-[Four-Nines speaking Binary]
[in English] I don't think my father's
ever had an apprentice.
Unless maybe it was an apprentice that
he had during the time he spent with you?
Can't be.
I would have known
if he had an apprentice.
[low whirring]
[Gennoh] Your thoughts?
[Zhima] Even a single large kyber crystal
would be difficult for this to handle.
And if we repaired it. it's likely
that we would end up with the same result.
[Gennoh] Disappointing.
General Nawaam. why don't we head
to Bibin and settle this?
[Nawaam] If we cannot use the cannon.
then we must wait.
Though of course.
there are other ways of fighting them.
[♪ thrilling music playing]
This is our plan of attack.
[beeps]
Our asteroid ships will jump into position
around Yaago.
[Homen] Then we will form an orbit
that mirrors an actual asteroid belt
and infiltrate Yaago's airspace.
[Kwana] Then we'll set the ships
on a collision course
with the enemy's so-called secret weapon
and slam right into it.
After we've infiltrated their flagship.
we'll need to evacuate
using their own small ships on board.
Ethan will make contact with my father
and bring him safely to us.
[Juro] Their weapon is reported
to be massive
and will likely have
heavy armor surrounding it.
But no matter how strong.
it won't stand a chance
against orbital asteroid strikes.
Our advantage is not in numbers
but in surprise.
We must strike the enemy
before they can repair the cannon.
[Kara. Kwana and Homen] Hmm.
[engine revving]
Thank you for all you have done for us.
We will now depart to find
a new place to call home.
-Kara...
-[grunts]
[Tafflah] I owe you my life
and my people should know that.
Thank you again.
-But also. I apologize.
-[Kara] Apologize?
I'm grateful for our conversation.
And I wish the very best
for you and your people.
May the Force be with you all.
-[citizens murmuring]
-[Kara gasps] Hmm.
[indistinct chatter]
Finally...
We're going to Yaago.
[♪ valiant music playing]
Now we depart for Yaago!
[all cheering]
Hmm.
[♪ theme music playing]
[♪ music ends]
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm